<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Ammar Shah</title>
 <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-11-04T18:57:21+05:00</updated>
 <id>ammaralishah.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Ammar Shah</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Ammar Says - It's here</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/10/25/ammar-says/"/>
   <updated>2015-10-25T01:50:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/10/25/ammar-says</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/.../assets/ammar-says.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ammar Says Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this listening to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deezer.com/track/76983689?utm_source=deezer&amp;amp;utm_content=track-76983689&amp;amp;utm_term=793525815_1445720257&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&quot;&gt;Hero by Family of the Year&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s an amazing song and you should listen to it. I first heard it while watching, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1065073/&quot;&gt;Boyhood&lt;/a&gt;, a few days ago. I don&amp;#39;t always listen to music when I&amp;#39;m writing but I&amp;#39;m addicted to Hero right now.  This post isn&amp;#39;t about the song, nor is it about Boyhood - it could be, but it isn&amp;#39;t.  This post is actually about my blog, &lt;em&gt;this blog&lt;/em&gt; which I&amp;#39;ve made some changes to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why the change?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I start with what has changed, I want to explain my plan to you all. As I &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/10/so-it-begins/&quot;&gt;stated before&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#39;ve been blogging since 2012 because I love writing and sharing my thought with all of you. In 2014, I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewormofficial.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;The Worm official&lt;/a&gt; and wrote a few posts there. I spent the last few months building &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewormofficial.github.io/&quot;&gt;a new home for The Worm Official&lt;/a&gt;. The last few weeks have been very tense for me as I was trying to decide a few things. Here&amp;#39;s a list of what I concluded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;ll be shutting down The Worm Official but the old site will still be up as an archive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My focus will be on writing on this blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since I like to talk on a lot of topics, I will not be limiting this blog to a specific topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As hard as it was for me, I&amp;#39;ve closed  &amp;quot;The Worm Official chapter&amp;quot; in my life and will soon be deleting it&amp;#39;s social accounts. This gives me time to focus more on this blog. I&amp;#39;ll be writing here completely from now on. As mentioned above, I will not be following a specific topic. I still haven&amp;#39;t decided the frequency of my posts but I&amp;#39;m sure I&amp;#39;ll decide that too at some point in the near future. Now that that&amp;#39;s done, here&amp;#39;s what has changed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Blog Name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/.../assets/blog-name.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ammar Says Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve decided to name this blog, &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Ammar Says&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;. The tagline accompanying this name is &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Freshly Published Thoughts on the world!&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmmarAliShahK&quot;&gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt; your thoughts on the name and tagline - I promise I don&amp;#39;t bite!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sidebar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/.../assets/sidebar.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ammar Says Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve also made some changes to the side/top nav of the site. On every page, you&amp;#39;ll see the description changes. I just thought it looked good. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmmarAliShahK&quot;&gt;What do you think?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Writing Archive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/.../assets/archive.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ammar Says Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added in a &lt;a href=&quot;/writing/&quot;&gt;writing archive&lt;/a&gt;. It lists all my posts that are available online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s everything I&amp;#39;ve changed visually. I also made a few changes that don&amp;#39;t really effect your experience so there&amp;#39;s no point in talking about that. I care a lot about User Experience and that&amp;#39;s why I want you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmmarAliShahK&quot;&gt;tell me&lt;/a&gt; about your experience because I care about you :))&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Droid Maxx Battery problems</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/10/24/droid-maxx-battery/"/>
   <updated>2015-10-24T08:50:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/10/24/droid-maxx-battery</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/droid-maxx.png&quot; alt=&quot;Droid Maxx&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, in August, I changed my smartphone and bought the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones/droid-maxx/m-droid-maxx.html&quot;&gt;Motorola Droid Maxx&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;ve been using the phone as my daily driver since and hadn&amp;#39;t run into a problem with it though it was the 16-gig version and I had to do a bit of memory management but everything else was great. The great thing about this phone is that it&amp;#39;s packed with a huge battery which is advertised to &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;last for up to 48 hours on a single charge&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;. I&amp;#39;m out a lot and this battery was just what I needed. Things would&amp;#39;ve been percect if I had bought the 32-gig version but you don&amp;#39;t get everything you wish for(and that&amp;#39;s okay).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/DroidMaxx1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Droid Maxx Battery&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks, the battery started draining really fast - 7 - 10 hours / charge. The phone also started to heat up a but if used constantly. As busy as I am, I didn&amp;#39;t put much thought into it until yesterday when I saw that it was really turning into a problem. A full charge(which would take up to 3 hours) was draining in just 7 hours! A little CPU intensive task would raise the temperature above 40°C!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick Google search and &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of forum reading gave me a lot of information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was not alone. A lot of other Droid Maxx owners were facing the same problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people started having this problem after they upgraded to Android 4.4 - my phone came with 4.4 pre-installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good news&lt;/strong&gt; - Most people were able to fix the problem by doing simple things such as re-calibrating the battery, or formatting the phone or clearing the cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve decided to give the &lt;em&gt;factory reset&lt;/em&gt; option a try. I&amp;#39;ll lose all my data in the process so I&amp;#39;m backing it all up to the cloud and my computer as I type this. Once it&amp;#39;s done, I&amp;#39;ll factory reset the phone and clear the cache too. I hope that&amp;#39;ll fix the problem. If not, I&amp;#39;m going to try re-calibrating the battery. If all fails, I&amp;#39;ll be contacting support but hopefully it won&amp;#39;t come to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve made small changes to the blog. I&amp;#39;m trying things out and once I think everything is the way I want it to be, I&amp;#39;ll be writing a post about the changes and explaining what I did and why I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Exploring New Horizons</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/09/25/new-horizon/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-25T01:01:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/09/25/new-horizon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/horizon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture by Huzefa Mustafa&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Picture by &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/huzefa_mustafa/&quot;&gt;Huzefa Mustafa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time has come for me to admit my crimes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t been loyal to this blog and to the people who read it. In my &lt;a href=&quot;http://ammaralishah.me/2015/07/10/so-it-begins/&quot;&gt;very first post&lt;/a&gt;, I promised I would fall into some kind of regularity of blogging after I start High School. A few weeks after that, when &lt;a href=&quot;http://ammaralishah.me/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x/&quot;&gt;I quit CS50&lt;/a&gt;, I made yet another promise that I would post about my code journey every week. I haven&amp;#39;t been able to fulfill either of those promises :-(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phew!&lt;/em&gt; Good thing I got that off my chest, I can sleep peacefully now. Am I done here then? Not quite... being the nice guy I am, I&amp;#39;m going to tell you exactly why I haven&amp;#39;t been able to keep my promises, or in-other-words, I&amp;#39;m going to play the blame game :))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR I blame my High School&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://ammaralishah.me/2015/07/10/so-it-begins/&quot;&gt;mentioned before&lt;/a&gt;, I started High School in the second week of August and had to adjust to my new schedule. Turns out, It&amp;#39;s practically impossible to do so. I leave for school at around 7 AM and return around 4 PM. By the time I change, shower and eat, It&amp;#39;s already over 5 PM. By the time I&amp;#39;m back to functioning properly, it&amp;#39;s over 7 PM and I have to start doing my homework which take two hours(yes they are trying to kill us). By 10 PM, I&amp;#39;m exhausted and just fall asleep. That&amp;#39;s my routine Monday through Friday. Hopefully this will earn me your sympathy and you&amp;#39;ll let me go for not keeping my promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR  I found better ways to track my progress while being productive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#39;ve laid out the practical impossibility of a blogging routine, I&amp;#39;m going to tell you about my weekends. Judging from my daily schedule, you might argue that I had time to write my weekly report on weekends, and you&amp;#39;re absolutely right. I could have written the weekly report, but I didn&amp;#39;t. At first, I forgot writing it every Sunday night and later on, I realized it was just another burden on me. I only had two free days every week and I could either be productive or worry about everything else I have to do. So I just made rough notes of what I did that day and decided to turn them into real posts later on(which I never did). &lt;strong&gt;So I&amp;#39;ve just decided to quit writing my weekly report&lt;/strong&gt;. The only reason I was writing them was to track my progress right, well FCC, GitHub and other tools I use are already doing that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FreeCodeCamp does a great job of tracking my daily progress so I don&amp;#39;t need to track it myself,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/FCC.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;FreeCodeCamp progress&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and so does GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/GHprog.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub tracking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That frees me of the responsibly to track my progress and I can focus more on learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, I expect you warm-hearted people have forgiven me for not keeping my word and sympathies with me and my class fellows and are going to spam &lt;a href=&quot;http://commecscollege.edu.pk/&quot;&gt;my school&lt;/a&gt; about the horrific timings. If that is the case, here&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@commecscollege.edu.pk&quot;&gt;their email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically this posts &lt;em&gt;officially&lt;/em&gt; announces my previous promises are now no longer valid. To make it up for that, I&amp;#39;m going to make new promises :))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to go through the backlog of this blog and I&amp;#39;m going to update/edit all of my posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to try to blog more often about things that I want to write about(I said I&amp;#39;ll try)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want me to stay true to my word, you might wanna bug my school so much that they shorten our timings. It&amp;#39;s almost 11 AM so I&amp;#39;m gonna go and eat breakfast. &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@commecscollege.edu.pk&quot;&gt;Spam my school&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>JavaScript pledge: Week 3</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/16/js-pledge-week3/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-16T16:50:22+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/16/js-pledge-week3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s Sunday night again and this marks the end of my third week for learning JavaScript. &lt;a href=&quot;e-learning/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x/&quot;&gt;As promised&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;#39;s my progress for the week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read chapter 0 of &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintohtml5.info/&quot;&gt;Dive into HTML5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I solved FCC Bonfire - &lt;a href=&quot;http://freecodecamp.com/challenges/bonfire-check-for-palindromes&quot;&gt;Check for Palindromes&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I solved FCC Bonfire - &lt;a href=&quot;http://freecodecamp.com/challenges/bonfire-find-the-longest-word-in-a-string&quot;&gt;Find the Longest Word in a String&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started reading Eloquent JavaScript from the start again&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started working on a new practice website(Haven&amp;#39;t completed it yet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s all I did this week. I hope I&amp;#39;ll do better next week!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>JavaScript pledge: Week 2</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/09/js-pledge-week2/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-09T16:50:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/09/js-pledge-week2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been 2 weeks since I took my &lt;a href=&quot;e-learning/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x/&quot;&gt;JavaScript pledge&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;#39;s Sunday night which means time for my weekly report. This week wasn&amp;#39;t productive at all and I did even worse than &lt;a href=&quot;/code/2015/08/02/js-pledge-week1/&quot;&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read Chapter 5 of Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read Learn HTML &amp;amp; CSS by Shay Howe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I built a practice website(HTML &amp;amp; CSS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solved the &amp;quot;reverse an array&amp;quot; challenge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s all I did this week. I hope I&amp;#39;ll do better next week!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Relearning RegEx</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/03/relearning-regex/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-03T16:26:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/03/relearning-regex</id>
   <content type="html"></content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>JavaScript pledge: Week 1</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/02/js-pledge-week1/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-02T16:50:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/08/02/js-pledge-week1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I recently &lt;a href=&quot;/e-learning/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x.html&quot;&gt;quit CS50x&lt;/a&gt; and in that post I stated I&amp;#39;d be writing about my progress every week till the end of the year. Well it&amp;#39;s Sunday and my time is up and as stated, this is y first weekly report. This week wasn&amp;#39;t as productive as I thought it would be due to some family events. I had to spend three complete days away from my house and computer(Wednesday, Friday and Sunday) so that put me a little behind on my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I completed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/challenges/waypoint-learn-regular-expressions&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp Waypoint: Learn regular expressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/04_data.html&quot;&gt;chapter 4&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completed &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AmmarAliShah/EloquentJavaScript-Solutions/blob/master/04_01.%20The%20sum%20of%20a%20range.js&quot;&gt;The sum of a range&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; exercise from &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/premium/courses/introduction-to-html-2897&quot;&gt;Introduction to HTML&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com&quot;&gt;Sitepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/premium/courses/introduction-to-responsive-web-design-2889&quot;&gt;Introduction to Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com&quot;&gt;Sitepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;/cert.jpg?raw=true&quot;&gt;Build Your First Website: Getting Started with HTML &amp;amp; CSS&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/&quot;&gt;Sitepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s all for this week. I know it&amp;#39;s not much but I&amp;#39;ll try improving next week. The whole point of this pledge is to track my progress and try to improve little by little every week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why I quit Harvard CS50</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-25T12:58:29+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This post is being reviewed and updated&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/CS50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CS50&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/cs50/permalink/562182657262117/&quot;&gt;long debate&lt;/a&gt;, this post has been updated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, as mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/10/so-it-begins/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I started Harvards famous Computer Science MOOC, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs50.harvard.edu/&quot;&gt;CS50&lt;/a&gt;, on edx. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidjmalan&quot;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt; is the reason for CS50s success. He&amp;#39;s very energetic and easily steals the attention of his audience. He is the second &lt;em&gt;teacher&lt;/em&gt; who has inspired me, the first one being, &lt;a href=&quot;http://simonallardice.com/&quot;&gt;Simon Allardice&lt;/a&gt;. Now back to CS50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Original Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strike&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In my &lt;a href=&quot;/updates/2015/07/10/so-it-begins.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-computer-science-harvardx-cs50x&quot;&gt;Harvards CS50&lt;/a&gt; on edx. Today, I decided to quit it and I un-enrolled from the class on edx. I made the decision after thinking on it long and hard so I&amp;#39;m not regretting what I did. Here&amp;#39;s why I quit:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To sum it up in a line, &lt;em&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t have time for it&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;#39;m a web developer meaning what I do is related to the web - websites and web-apps. The course teaches C, a language not built for the web. My main focus was learning full-stack JavaScript and not C. When I started the course, I thought I would be able to do complete it without interference to my commitment to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;, which is to start the non-profit projects before the end of 2015! Sadly enough, in the past month, I haven&amp;#39;t made much progress there either. CS50x was not in any way my reason for not being able to keep my commitment to freecodecamp, I just got distracted.
&lt;/p&gt;
So today, I decided to remove all other distractions from my JavaScript learning path and focus on learning JavaScript. For the rest of they year, I&amp;#39;m going to learn and practice JavaScript only. I won&amp;#39;t play with any other language such as C or Python.
&lt;h2&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So there&amp;#39;s a few things I&amp;#39;ll be doing to keep focused on JavaScript:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; I&amp;#39;m going to read &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; I&amp;#39;m going to complete at least one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; challenge every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Every week, i.e every Sunday night, I&amp;#39;ll be posting about my progress of the previous week.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
This is it. By the end of this year, I&amp;#39;ll have made good progress if everything goes as planned :)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strike&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>So it begins</title>
   <link href="ammaralishah.github.io/2015/07/10/so-it-begins/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-10T10:38:29+05:00</updated>
   <id>ammaralishah.github.io/2015/07/10/so-it-begins</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/hello-world.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hello World&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m growing tired of this! &lt;em&gt;This?&lt;/em&gt; Writing this, &lt;code&gt;Hello world&lt;/code&gt; post. This is the third time I&amp;#39;m writing this and this time I decided to change the title - much better, &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#39;t you think?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Third Time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I discovered blogging in 2012, I&amp;#39;ve set up several blogs on various topics, and have deleted or &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ammarshah/how-i-lost-my-blog-24b31e300199&quot;&gt;lost them&lt;/a&gt;. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com&quot;&gt;Google Blogger&lt;/a&gt; for my first few blogs and then over the years, used many other solutions such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://modx.com/&quot;&gt;MODX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightcms.com/&quot;&gt;LightCMS&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot more. Each blog had a life span of a few months. Here I&amp;#39;m only going to talk about the personal blogs I had/have setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote the first one titled &lt;code&gt;Ello World&lt;/code&gt; back when I started my personal blog in early 2015 but sadly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ammarshah/how-i-lost-my-blog-24b31e300199&quot;&gt;I lost it!&lt;/a&gt;. My first blog was based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and hosted for free at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.000webhost.com/690150.html&quot;&gt;000WebHost&lt;/a&gt;. The problem with this setup was that it was ad-supported and on every refresh or load an ad popped up which was annoying!  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My second blog, sadly never made it to the internet. I set it up a few weeks ago, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; and it was hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;. Now Ghost isn&amp;#39;t natively supported on GitHub pages, as it only allows static sites and Ghost is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;. So, I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://leftofnull.com/2014/02/07/using-github-pages-with-ghost-and-buster-on-windows-part-1/index.html&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, that used a set of tools to let you run Ghost on GitHub pages. Following the instructions, I successfully set up Ghost on my local machine and configured it. That is when I wrote, this post for the second time, titled &lt;code&gt;Ello World...Again&lt;/code&gt;. I ran into a problem with Buster with that setup and after numerous tries I couldn&amp;#39;t fix it. I contacted the author of the post through Twitter, and I even commented on the post, but after a little back and fro, I gave up! I even got a Tweet from someone telling me the CSS on my site was broken - something I didn&amp;#39;t notice. So I decided to try something else.
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmmarAliShahK&quot;&gt;@AmmarAliShahK&lt;/a&gt; I think your CSS is broken on your website &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/bXAJwIDRpm&quot;&gt;http://t.co/bXAJwIDRpm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Matthew Harames (@MatthewHarames) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MatthewHarames/status/617758469584654336&quot;&gt;July 5, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the third and current state -  &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, is built by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, the same company whose service I was using to host my site so I thought you can&amp;#39;t get more compatible than that, right? So I started with Jekyll and ran into problems with the final site again. So I explored other popular static site generators from the list at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticgen.com/&quot;&gt;StaticGen&lt;/a&gt;. After trying out around a dozen other options and facing the same problem, I concluded I was doing something wrong. So I Googled around, and after a little playing around with Jekyll(actually a lot playing around), I finally nailed it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I plan on sticking with this for a while. I don&amp;#39;t know for sure right now, but I will re-design the site in the future, but right now, I don&amp;#39;t have the time or the energy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m still working through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/ammaralishah&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://courses.edx.org/courses/HarvardX/CS50x3/2015/info&quot;&gt;Harvard CS50x&lt;/a&gt; on edx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I gave &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/chinese-language-learn-basic-mandarin-mandarinx-mx101x&quot;&gt;learning Mandarin&lt;/a&gt; a try but I bailed out after just one day!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got a haircut :-D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;And?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#39;s it. I plan on blogging regularly but I can&amp;#39;t say for sure right now. My High School starts from August 11 and I&amp;#39;m gonna try to fit blogging into my routine. I&amp;#39;m working on a project atm and maybe I&amp;#39;ll  write about that in an upcoming post/posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
