<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ammar Shah</title>
    <description>Ammar Shah is a freelance developer based in Karachi, Pakistan.
</description>
    <link>http://ammaralishah.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ammaralishah.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:19:30 +0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:19:30 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Relearning RegEx</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 16:26:00 +0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ammaralishah.me/code/2015/08/03/relearning-regex.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ammaralishah.me/code/2015/08/03/relearning-regex.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>JavaScript pledge: Week 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I recently &lt;a href=&quot;/e-learning/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x.html&quot;&gt;quit CS50x&lt;/a&gt; and in that post I stated I’d be writing about my progress every week till the end of the year. Well it’s Sunday and my time is up and as stated, this is y first weekly report. This week wasn’t as productive as I thought it would be due to some family events. I had to spend three complete days away from my house and computer(Wednesday, Friday and Sunday) so that put me a little behind on my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I completed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/challenges/waypoint-learn-regular-expressions&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp Waypoint: Learn regular expressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/04_data.html&quot;&gt;chapter 4&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completed “&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AmmarAliShah/EloquentJavaScript-Solutions/blob/master/04_01.%20The%20sum%20of%20a%20range.js&quot;&gt;The sum of a range&lt;/a&gt;” exercise from &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/premium/courses/introduction-to-html-2897&quot;&gt;Introduction to HTML&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com&quot;&gt;Sitepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/premium/courses/introduction-to-responsive-web-design-2889&quot;&gt;Introduction to Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com&quot;&gt;Sitepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;/cert.jpg?raw=true&quot;&gt;Build Your First Website: Getting Started with HTML &amp;amp; CSS&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/&quot;&gt;Sitepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this week. I know it’s not much but I’ll try improving next week. The whole point of this pledge is to track my progress and try to improve little by little every week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 16:50:00 +0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ammaralishah.me/code/2015/08/02/js-pledge-week1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ammaralishah.me/code/2015/08/02/js-pledge-week1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I quit Harvard CS50x</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/updates/2015/07/10/so-it-begins.html&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-computer-science-harvardx-cs50x&quot;&gt;Harvards CS50x&lt;/a&gt; on edx. Today, I decided to quit it and I un-enrolled from the class on edx. I made the decision after thinking on it long and hard so I’m not regretting what I did. Here’s why I quit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum it up in a line, &lt;em&gt;I didn’t have time for it.&lt;/em&gt; I’m a web developer meaning what I do is related to the web - websites and web-apps. The course teaches C, a language not built for the web. My main focus was learning full-stack JavaScript and not C. When I started the course, I thought I would be able to do complete it without interference to my commitment to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;, which is to start the non-profit projects before the end of 2015! Sadly enough, in the past month, I haven’t made much progress there either. CS50x was not in any way my reason for not being able to keep my commitment to freecodecamp, I just got distracted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, I decided to remove all other distractions from my JavaScript learning path and focus on learning JavaScript. For the rest of they year, I’m going to learn and practice JavaScript only. I won’t play with any other language such as C or Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aftermath&quot;&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there’s a few things I’ll be doing to keep focused on JavaScript:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’m going to read &lt;a href=&quot;http://eloquentjavascript.net/&quot;&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’m going to complete at least one &lt;a href=&quot;http://freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; challenge every day&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Every week, i.e every Sunday night, I’ll be posting about my progress of the previous week.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it. By the end of this year, I’ll have made good progress if everything goes as planned :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 12:58:29 +0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ammaralishah.me/e-learning/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ammaralishah.me/e-learning/2015/07/25/leaving-cs50x.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>e-learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So it begins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/hello-world.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hello World&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m growing tired of this! &lt;em&gt;This?&lt;/em&gt; Writing this, &lt;code&gt;Hello world&lt;/code&gt; post. This is the third time I’m writing this and this time I decided to change the title - much better, don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-you-write-it-thrice&quot;&gt;Why did you write it thrice?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I discovered blogging in 2012, I’ve set up many blogs and have deleted or &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ammarshah/how-i-lost-my-blog-24b31e300199&quot;&gt;lost them&lt;/a&gt;. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com&quot;&gt;Google Blogger&lt;/a&gt; for my first few blogs and then over the years, used many other solutions such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://modx.com/&quot;&gt;MODX&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightcms.com/&quot;&gt;LightCMS&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot more. All my blogs were on different subjects and lasted a few months before I deleted them. Here I’m only going to talk about the personal blogs I’ve setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wrote the first one titled &lt;code&gt;Ello World&lt;/code&gt; back when I started my blog in early 2015 but sadly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ammarshah/how-i-lost-my-blog-24b31e300199&quot;&gt;I lost it!&lt;/a&gt;. My first blog was based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and hosted for free at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.000webhost.com/690150.html&quot;&gt;000WebHost&lt;/a&gt;. The problem with this setup was that it was ad-supported and on every refresh or load an ad popped up which was annoying!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My second blog, sadly never made it to the internet. I set it up a few weeks ago, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; and it was hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;. Now Ghost isn’t natively supported on GitHub pages, as it only allows static sites and Ghost is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;. So, I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://leftofnull.com/2014/02/07/using-github-pages-with-ghost-and-buster-on-windows-part-1/index.html&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, that used a set of tools to let you run Ghost on GitHub pages. Following the instructions, I successfully set up Ghost on my local machine and configured it. That is when I wrote, this post for the second time, titled &lt;code&gt;Ello World...Again&lt;/code&gt;. I ran into a problem with Buster with that setup and after numerous tries I couldn’t fix it. I contacted the author of the post through Twitter, and I even commented on the post, but after a little back and fro, I gave up! I even got a Tweet from someone telling me the CSS on my site was broken - something I didn’t notice. So I decided to try something else.
 &lt;img src=&quot;/../assets/siteBrokenTweet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Tweet I got&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This brings us to my third and current state, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll, is built by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, the same company whose service I was using to host my site so I thought you can’t get more compatible than that, right? So I started with Jekyll and ran into problems with the final site again. So I explored other popular static site generators from the list at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticgen.com/&quot;&gt;StaticGen&lt;/a&gt;. After trying out around a dozen other options and facing the same problem, I concluded I was doing something wrong. So I Googled around, and after a little playing around with Jekyll(actually a lot playing around), I finally nailed it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I plan on sticking with this for a while. I don’t know for sure right now, but I will re-design the site in the future, but right now, I don’t have the time or the energy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m still working through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://courses.edx.org/courses/HarvardX/CS50x3/2015/info&quot;&gt;Harvard CS50x&lt;/a&gt; on edx&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I gave &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/chinese-language-learn-basic-mandarin-mandarinx-mx101x&quot;&gt;learning Mandarin&lt;/a&gt; a try but I bailed out after just one day!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got a haircut :-D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and&quot;&gt;And?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s it. I plan on blogging regularly but I can’t say for sure right now. My college starts from August and I’m gonna try to fit blogging into my routine. Till then, I’m working on a &lt;em&gt;non-profit&lt;/em&gt; project atm(not from &lt;a href=&quot;http://freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;) and I’ll be writing about that in an upcoming post/posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 10:38:29 +0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ammaralishah.me/updates/2015/07/10/so-it-begins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ammaralishah.me/updates/2015/07/10/so-it-begins.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
