<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ammar Shah</title>
    <description>Ammar Shah is a freelance developer based in Karachi, Pakistan.
</description>
    <link>http://ammaralishah.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ammaralishah.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 02:13:56 +0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 02:13:56 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>So it begins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m growing tired of this! &lt;em&gt;This?&lt;/em&gt; Writing this &lt;code&gt;Hello world&lt;/code&gt; post. I’m writing it for the third time now and this time, I wanted
to change the title from my classic &lt;code&gt;Ello World&lt;/code&gt;, and so I changed it to this, much better don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Writing it for the third time?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah. I wrote the first one titled &lt;code&gt;Ello World&lt;/code&gt; back when I started my blog in early 2015 but sadly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ammarshah/how-i-lost-my-blog-24b31e300199&quot;&gt;I lost it!&lt;/a&gt;. My first blog was based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and hosted for free at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;000WebHost&lt;/a&gt;. The problem with this setup was that it was ad-supported and on every refresh or load an ad popped up which was annoying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second blog, sadly never made it to the internet. I set it up a few weeks ago, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; and it was hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;. Now Ghost isn’t natively supported on GitHub pages, as it only allows static sites and Ghost is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;. So, I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://leftofnull.com/2014/02/07/using-github-pages-with-ghost-and-buster-on-windows-part-1/index.html&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, that used a set of tools to let you run Ghost on GitHub pages. Following the instructions, I successfully set up Ghost locally on my computer and configured it. That is when I wrote, this post for the second time, titled &lt;code&gt;Ello World...Again&lt;/code&gt;. I ran into a problem with Buster with that setup and after numerous tries I couldn’t fix it. I contacted the author of the post through Twitter, and I even commented on the post, but after a little back and fro, I gave up! I even got a Tweet from someone telling me the CSS on my site was broken - something I didn’t notice. So I decided to try something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ammaralishah.me/assets/siteBrokenTweet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Tweet I got&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to my third and current state, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll, is built by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, the same company whose service I was using to host my site so I thought you can’t get more compatible than that, right? So I started with Jekyll and again ran into problems with the final site again. So I explored other popular static site generators from the list at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticgen.com/&quot;&gt;StaticGen&lt;/a&gt;. After trying out around a dozen other options and facing the same problem, I concluded I was doing something wrong. So I Googled around, and after a little playing around with Jekyll(actually a lot playing around), I finally nailed it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So now what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I plan on sticking with this for a while. I don’t know for sure right now, but I will re-designt the site in the future, but right now, I don’t have the time or the energy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m still working through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://courses.edx.org/courses/HarvardX/CS50x3/2015/info&quot;&gt;Harvard CS50x&lt;/a&gt; on edx&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I gave learning Mandarin a try but I bailed out after just one day!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got a haircut :-D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s it. I plan on blogging regularly but I can’t say for sure right now. My college starts from August and I’m gonna try to fit blogging into my routine. Till then, I’m working on a &lt;em&gt;non-profit&lt;/em&gt; project atm(not from FreeCodeCamp) and I’ll be writing about that in an upcoming post/posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 10:38:29 +0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ammaralishah.me/blog/updates/2015/07/10/so-it-begins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ammaralishah.me/blog/updates/2015/07/10/so-it-begins.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
